MARCELO ARAÚJO

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

marcelomaidden@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with over ten years of experience in the public sector. Self-motivated and fast learner proficient with Linux and Windows Operating Systems. Looking to develop software that can help peoples' lives to be easier.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, MySQL, Python, Diango

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS Full Stack Web Developer

Remote Sep 2020 – Present

Slack bot to retrieve Google Calendar — Slack bot APP that retrieves all Calendars and upcoming events when they are mentioned on Slack conversations.

Built with: Ruby

News Week Website's clone - Responsive website's design based on News Week website.

Built with: (HTML, CSS, and Twitter Bootstrap framework)

MICROVERSE Mentor (Volunteer)

Remote

Oct 2020 - Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

INSTITUTO FEDERAL DE EDUCAÇÃO, CIÊNCIA E TECNOLOGIA DE SÃO PAULO

Campos do Jordão, Brazil

I.T Technician I.T. Support in software development and network infrastructure

Oct 2010 - Present

- Created a system to automate students' grades' calculations, attendance scores, decreasing by 90% the time teachers spent
 calculating it by hand.
- Redesigned network infrastructure using VLANs, allowing different networks to share resources and each network to have its own rules.
- Virtualized Operating Systems using Citrix XenServer, which helped in a better distribution of Server Resources.
- Created Docker containers to provide services faster, decreasing considerably the amount of time spent to start new network services.
- Participated in Active Directory Samba 4's implementation, which was important to centralize user credentials and information that could be used in different systems.
- Implemented GLPI to create support tickets providing teams to open support calls, which reduced in 70% time spent to solve the company's team's issues.
- Implemented Fusion Inventory attached to GLPI to provide Network Devices' inventory, which helped make reports from network
 equipment and best divide resources.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

Sep, 2020 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1191+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

INSTITUTO FEDERAL DE EDUCAÇÃO, CIÊNCIA E TECNOLOGIA DE SÃO PAULO Bachelor's Degree, System Analysis and Development

Jan, 2012 - Dec, 2014